{
  "reference_number": "2194",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The science behind climate change caused by carbon dioxide and methane is 100% flawed. Not one single study has quantified the\n\n effects of green house gases except by correlating GHG emissions with so called temperature increases. The temperature data used\n by all the green house gas alarmists is highly flawed. ie the homogenisations (changing) of urban temperature station data due to the\n UHI (URBAN HEAT ISLAND EFFECT) is highly flawed by a non transperant process of adjustment. The global satellite temperature data\n\n + unhomogenised rural station temperature data is the only reliable temperature data to observe and model. Further, not one single\n research group across the world has applied basic thermodynamics to this issue of \"how does human emitted carbon dioxide due to\n fossil fuels\" affect temperature. I have applied basic thermodynamics to my temperature modelling and its so very clear that water\n\n vapour dominates the thermodynamics (due to a combination of its significantly higher % in the atmosphere (0.986% to over 4%in\n the tropics) compared to current CO2 levels of 400 ppm = 0.04% across the globe. Further the heat capacity of water\n\n vapour/aqueous water is 4000 J/kgdegC compared to 700 J/kgdegC for CO2. ie water absorbs 571% more heat to raise the\n temperature by 1 degC than carbon dioxide. The corrollary is that reducing the carbon dioxide to zero (or 280 ppm being the\n preindustrial level) will actually INCREASE the temperature-NOT DECREASE the temperature. Raising the CO2 amount by doubling it\n\n from say current 400 ppm levels to 800ppm levels will INCREASE the atmospheric temperatures. The temperature cycles are primarily\n driven by natural solar cycles, not green house gases. And 97% of scientists do not agree with Al Gores prognosis-nor do 97% of\n\n scientists agree with the prognosis that increasing CO2 is increasing the global temperatures. Check out the latest global satellite\n temperature data which has been decreasing since 2016 despite increasing CO2."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Impossible to implement any emmission reductions but further-reducing emmissions to reduce global temperatures has zero\n\n scientific basis and as such wont make one iota of difference. Suns solar / planetary cycles and water vapour rule!!!!"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "Even changing the emmissions budget by whatever technology wont make any difference whatsoever!!"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "See all of the above comments."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "To change the suns cycles and planetary orbits which drive climate change is going to be a herculean task for the Govt!!! But if they\ncan change the earths planetary orbits and the solar output then they will be some Govt that the world will certainly listen to!"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "NO."
    }
  ]
}
